<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2009 Lutris -->
<component type="desktop">
  <id>net.lutris.Lutris</id>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <translation type="gettext">lutris</translation>
  <developer_name translatable="no">Lutris Team</developer_name>
  <update_contact>mathieucomandon@gmail.com</update_contact>
  <name translatable="no">Lutris</name>
  <summary>Video game preservation platform</summary>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main window</caption>
      <image>https://lutris.net/static/images/lutris-window-2023.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <description><p>Lutris helps you install and play video games from all eras and from most gaming systems. By leveraging and combining existing emulators, engine re-implementations and compatibility layers, it gives you a central interface to launch all your games.</p></description>
  <url type="homepage">https://lutris.net</url>
  <url type="donation">https://lutris.net/donate</url>
  <url type="help">https://forums.lutris.net</url>
  <url type="faq">https://lutris.net/faq</url>
  <url type="translate">https://github.com/lutris/lutris/tree/master/po</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/lutris/lutris/issues</url>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.lutris.Lutris.desktop</launchable>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.5.16" date="2024-01-15" urgency="low">
      <description>
        <ul>
           <li>Fix bug that prevented installers to complete</li>
           <li>Better handling of Steam configurations for the Steam account picker</li>
           <li>Load game library in a background thread</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.15" date="2024-01-07" urgency="low">
      <description>
        <ul>
           <li>Fix some  crashes happening when using Wayland and a high DPI gaming mouse</li>
           <li>Fix crash when opening the system preferences tab for a game</li>
           <li>Reduced the locales list to a predefined one (let us know if you need yours added)</li>
           <li>Fix Lutris not expanding "~" in paths</li>
           <li>Download runtime components from the main window,</li>
           <li>the "updating runtime" dialog appearing before Lutris opens has been removed</li>
           <li>Add the ability to open a location in your file browser from file picker widgets</li>
           <li>Add the ability to select, remove, or stop multiple games in the Lutris window</li>
           <li>Redesigned 'Uninstall Game' dialog now completely removes games by default</li>
           <li>Fix the export / import feature</li>
           <li>Show an animation when a game is launched</li>
           <li>Add the ability to disable Wine auto-updates at the expense of losing support</li>
           <li>Add playtime editing in the game preferences</li>
           <li>Move game files, runners to the trash instead of deleting them they are uninstalled</li>
           <li>Add "Updates" tab in Preferences control and check for updates and correct missing media</li>
           <li>in the 'Games' view.</li>
           <li>Add "Storage" tab in Preferences to control game and installer cache location</li>
           <li>Expand "System" tab in Preferences with more system information but less brown.</li>
           <li>Add "Run Task Manager" command for Wine games</li>
           <li>Add two new, smaller banner sizes for itch.io games.</li>
           <li>Ignore Wine virtual desktop setting when using Wine-GE/Proton to avoid crash</li>
           <li>Ignore MangoHUD setting when launching Steam to avoid crash</li>
           <li>Sync Steam playtimes with the Lutris library</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.14" date="2023-10-16" urgency="low">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add Steam account switcher to handle multiple Steam accounts</li>
          <li>on the same device.</li>
          <li>Add user defined tags / categories</li>
          <li>Group every API calls for runtime updates in a single one</li>
          <li>Download appropriate DXVK and VKD3D versions based on</li>
          <li>the available GPU PCI IDs</li>
          <li>EA App integration. Your Origin games and saves can be manually imported</li>
          <li>from your Origin prefix.</li>
          <li>Add integration with ScummVM local library</li>
          <li>Download Wine-GE updates when Lutris starts</li>
          <li>Group GOG and Amazon download in a single progress bar</li>
          <li>Fix blank login window on online services such as GOG or EGS</li>
          <li>Add a sort name field</li>
          <li>Yuzu and xemu now use an AppImage</li>
          <li>Experimental support for Flatpak provided runners</li>
          <li>Header-bar search for configuration options</li>
          <li>Support for Gamescope 3.12</li>
          <li>Missing games show an additional badge</li>
          <li>Add missing dependency on python3-gi-cairo for Debian packages</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.5.13" date="2023-05-16"  />
  </releases>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>
